ALEX THOMPSON

+886 968-780-902 · alex@alexthompson.work · alexthompson.work

Master of Science in Cartography and GIS, with a focus on emerging trends in web mapping and data visualization. Experience in application development, business analysis, project and team management, and geospatial analysis. Adaptable attitude and a demonstrated ability to excel in fast-paced environments.

Education

University of Wisconsin-Madison

Master of Science in Cartography and GIS

4.0/4.0

September 2018

Coursework focused on web map development, spatial analysis techniques, UI/UX design relevant to interactive cartography, and big data visualization.

National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency

Intermediate Geographic Intelligence Specialist Course

Honor Graduate

October 2014

Completed advanced courses in the fields of geodetic surveying and geospatial analysis.

Basic Geographic Intelligence Specialist Course

Distinguished Graduate

November 2012

Completed over 820 hours of study in geodetic surveying and geospatial analysis.

Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University

Bachelor of Science in Business Management with a Minor in Leadership

May 2007

Coursework focused on Entrepreneurship, Innovation, and Technology. Member of the Student Government Association Student Senate, the Student Government Association Budget Board, and the Entrepreneurial Leadership Initiative.

Professional Experience

United States Marine Corps

Geospatial Intelligence Chief, 3rd Marine Logistics Group G-2

April 2015 — *November* 2016

- Provided geospatial intelligence support to the Commanding General of 3rd Marine Logistics Group (MLG), in addition to the 12 subordinate units that make up MLG
- Managed the planning, production, and dissemination of over 500 geospatial products—a tenfold increase over the previous period
- Established a digital library to organize over 500 gigabytes of geospatial data, drastically reducing time spent on product production and maintenance
- Coordinated with a third-party contractor to implement a networked storage and backup solution, streamlining the G-2's infrastructure and enabling faster data sharing between teams
- Built custom geoprocessing models and Python scripts to automate repetitive tasks, improving both data intake and production speeds
- Implemented standard operating procedures and quality controls to facilitate faster daily production
- Awarded the Navy and Marine Corps Commendation Medal for work done streamlining the data infrastructure and increasing fusion between the different intelligence sections
- Nominated for the Military Member of the Quarter award through the National System for Geospatial-Intelligence Awards Program

ALEX THOMPSON

Geospatial Intelligence Analyst, 3rd Intelligence Battalion

December 2012 — April 2015

- · Collected, analyzed, and processed geospatial data to aid in the production of intelligence products
- Produced intelligence products in support of the III Marine Expeditionary Force and the 36 countries that fall under its area of responsibility in the Asia-Pacific region
- Worked with multiple service branches, civilian intelligence agencies, and multinational partners as part
 of regular operational duties, training exercises, and real-world operations
- Created a specialized GIS training program for Army intelligence analysts while attached to the 1st Special Forces Group
- Meritoriously promoted in June of 2013

Geospatial Intelligence Student

December 2011 — December 2012

 Completed over 820 hours of study in geodetic surveying and geospatial analysis at the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency

Self-Employed

Freelance Developer

June 2010 — November 2011

- Worked with a startup company to explore potential frontend interfaces, from design to rough implementation in HTML and CSS
- Executed contracts with multiple e-commerce customers, primarily working on backends written in PHP

Progress Energy

Associate IT Analyst

June 2007 — June 2010

- · Connected internal customers and developers by translating business needs into technical requirements
- Coordinated with cross-functional teams to plan and execute projects
- Developed in-house enterprise software solutions using C# and ASP.NET
- Worked with vendors to implement third-party software solutions
- Managed a software product portfolio of more than a dozen applications

Technical Skills

Geospatial Analysis ArcGIS, QGIS, GRASS, GDAL/OGR, Leaflet, D3, Mapbox, Turf, OpenStreetMap

Development HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, React, Redux, Laravel PHP, Python,

C#, .NET, Java

Data Management MySQL, PostgreSQL, PostGIS, Git/GitHub

Key Applications Photoshop, Illustrator, Sketch, Unity